VINCENT R. TAIJERON

6/3 Shevchenko Ave, Odessa, Ukraine 65000

Phone: +38 067 371 4805

E-Mail: vincent.taijeron@gmail.com

Web: www.taijeronv.info

Professional Summary

I am a competent and reliable military professional with 15+ years of experience training, educating, and operating in the military domain. I am eager to contribute my experience and skills to a team of professionals dedicated to developing organizations and individuals to meet their full potential.

Work History

Monitoring Officer, Sep 2014 to Current, Pacific Architects and Engineers, Odessa, Ukraine

- Standardized team patrols by applying military planning methods improving the team's coordination and efficiency during operations.
- Planned and supervised the execution of four "2nd of May" patrols, ensuring the team's safety.
- Effectively managed a team of 21 individual personalities ensuring a peaceful work environment.
- Monitored over 400 kilometers of the Transnistrian border, providing the OSCE with accurate information regarding the security situation.

Curriculum Developer, Aug 2013 to Sep 2014, Alion Science and Technology, Odessa, Ukraine

- Advised the Commandant Major General Gulayk on the best way to integrate our NATO program into the 2015 academic year curriculum.
- Designed and taught a program of instruction to 2nd, 3rd, and 4th-year cadets, furthering their understanding of NATO operations.
- Taught the cadets how to improve their tactical-decision making using the "Follow Me" program.
- Developed a block of instruction featuring NATO mechanized infantry and armor operations for 35 students attending the Captain's Advanced Course, giving them an in-depth understanding.

Embedded Police Mentor, Jun 2011 to Aug 2013, DynCorp International FOB Salerno, Afghanistan

- Mentored a special unit of 10 Afghan patrolmen tasked with augmenting coalition forces and securing FOB Salerno.
- Developed and taught a one-week induction program to my ten-man police unit, improving their ability to operate with their US Army partners.
- Assisted 33 patrolmen in planning independent night patrols.
- Participated in over 50 mounted and dismounted combat patrols with the US Army while advising the Afghan police.

Simulation Center Manager, August 2004 to June 2011, West Point West Point, NY

- Enhanced the Military Science 3 and 4 programs by integrating the "Follow Me" program, which was used to practice making tactical decisions.
- Incorporated the Follow Me simulation into three military science courses, one college major (Defense Strategic Studies and two leadership courses for the Department of Behavioral Science and Leadership.
- Assisted instructor's in using the "Follow Me" program to achieve class learning outcomes in decision-making.
- Integrated Virtual Battlespace 2 into cadet basic training, providing over 1000 cadets an opportunity to practice squad fire and movement techniques before going to the field.
- Increased use of the Simulation Center by 100%.

Skills

Military Training and Education Operations and Planning Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook)
Leadership Management Writing

Education

Central Texas College, General Studies Guam Community College, Technical Electronics